Inhuman ecstasy fulfilled.
Possession is a horror film directed by Andrzej Żuławski.
A young woman left her family for an unspecified reason.
The husband determines to find out the truth and starts following his wife.
At first, he suspects that a man is involved.
But gradually, he finds out more and more strange behaviors and bizarre
incidents that indicate something more than a possessed love affair.
Anna / Helen, played by Isabelle Adjani.
Mark, played by Sam Neill.
Margit Gluckmeister, played by Margit Carstensen.
Heinrich, played by Heinz Bennent.
Heinrich's Mother, played by Johanna Hofer.
Private Detective, played by Carl Duering.
Possession is a 1981 psychological horror drama film directed by
Andrzej Żuławski and written by Żuławski and Frederic Tuten.
The plot obliquely follows the relationship between an international spy (Sam Neill) and his wife (Isabelle
Adjani), who begins exhibiting increasingly disturbing behavior after asking for a divorce.
Possession, an international co-production between France and
West Germany, was filmed in West Berlin in 1980.
Żuławski's only English-language film, it premiered at the 34th Cannes Film
Festival, where Adjani won the Best Actress award for her performance.
The screenplay was written during the painful divorce of
Żuławski from actress Małgorzata Braunek.
While not commercially successful either in Europe or in the United States, with the latter only receiving a heavily edited cut on
its initial release, the film eventually acquired cult status and has been more positively appraised in later years.
The film explores themes of adultery, berlin,
germany, monster, police, marriage crisis.
The tone is dark.